(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
5周年記念 & 新衣装お披露目ライブ
5th Anniversary & New Costume Unveiling Live
from A to Z
歌を歌う意味を
The meaning of singing songs
生き続けていく意味を
The meaning of continuing to live
考えても答えなんてないとしってる
I know there's no answer even if I think about it
白も黒も世界から消えた
White and black disappeared from the world
そこに何が残るのだろうか
What will remain there?
いなくなったら忘れてしまうか
Will you forget if I'm gone?
違う 違う 奇跡がここにあるよ
No, no, a miracle is right here
たった一人の君と出会えて
Meeting you, the only one
私は今を生きているの
I am living in the now
これから起こるすべてのことを
Everything that will happen from now on
一緒に見よう 最初から最後までだよ
Let's see it together, from beginning to end
今日はAZKiの5周年ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to AZKi's 5th Anniversary Live today!
開拓者のみんな、一緒に歌ってね！
Pioneers, let's sing together!
歌を歌う意味を
The meaning of singing songs
生き続けていく意味を
The meaning of continuing to live
一歩一歩確かめるように見つけよう
Let's find it as if confirming step by step
時に暗く冷たい世界で
In a world that is sometimes dark and cold
弱く脆く崩れそうになる
Becoming weak, fragile, and about to crumble
いなくなったら忘れてしまうか
Will you forget if I'm gone?
違う 違う 君の声が聞こえた
No, no, I heard your voice
たった一人の君と出会えて
Meeting you, the only one
私は今を生きているの
I am living in the now
これから起こるすべてのことを
Everything that will happen from now on
一緒に綴ろう 最初から最後までだよ
Let's write it together, from beginning to end
この世界を
This world...
大好きでいたいよ
I want to love it
時計の針が零時を指した
The clock hands pointed to midnight
気が遠くなるような時間が過ぎた
An unimaginable amount of time has passed
世界は変わる　そこに君はいない
The world changes, and you're not there
それでもいいと思えたんだよ
But I felt that was okay
たった一人の君と出会えて
Meeting you, the only one
私は今を生きているの
I am living in the now
今まで起きたすべてのことを
Everything that has happened until now
覚えていてね　最初から最後らだよ
Please remember them, from the beginning to the very end
ここがスタート
This is the start
歌を歌う意味を
The meaning of singing songs
生き続けていく意味を
The meaning of continuing to live
今やっとね　見つけたような気がしたよ
I feel like I've finally found them now
みなさん、こんあずきー！
Hello everyone, Kon-AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！
Mic in my right hand, map in my left, I'm the GeoGuesser of your heart!
ということで、みなさんAZKi 5th Anniversary Live "with U -みんなと一緒にこれからも-" にお越しいただき...
And so, everyone, thank you for coming to AZKi 5th Anniversary Live "with U -Together with Everyone from Now on-"...
...ありがとうございます！
...thank you very much!
わーい！
Yay!
ということで、一曲目は「from A to Z」お送りいたしました。
And so, the first song was "from A to Z."
はい、ま、この曲で今日も始めたいなと思って、今日も、えっと、セトリも演出もいろいろ頑張って考えてきましたので、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, well, I wanted to start today with this song too, and I've worked hard on the setlist and production, so please look forward to it.
ということで、ま、五周年をAZKi迎えることができました。本当にみんなの応援のおかげでここまで、えー、歩いてこれたと思っています。
So, AZKi was able to reach her 5th anniversary. I believe I've been able to walk this far thanks to everyone's support.
今日は、え、AZKi五周年ライブということでこちらのハッシュタグでぜひぜひスクショや、え、ポスト、ポスト、呟いてください。
Today is the AZKi 5th Anniversary Live, so please take screenshots and post/tweet using this hashtag.
ということで今日はですね、事前に告知しておりますが、
So today, as announced beforehand,
え、お披露目、新衣装のお披露目あり、ゲストパートあり、
there will be a new outfit reveal, a guest part,
最後に、お約束の告知と、さらに嬉しいお知らせもあり、ということで、最後までお見逃しなく！
and finally, the usual announcement along with some more happy news, so don't miss it until the end!
そして、早速ですがみんな気づきましたか？
And, first of all, did everyone notice?
この後ろに開拓者がいます！わーい！
There are Pioneers behind me! Yay!
わーい！開拓者ー！
Yay! Pioneers!
バーチャルの世界に3D化して現れてくれました！わーいわーいわーいわーい！
They've appeared in the virtual world in 3D! Yay yay yay yay!
はい、ということで、開拓者とはですね、アンコールでいっぱい触れ、戯れようと思っていますので、ぜひアンコールライブもよろしくお願いします。
Yes, and so, I'm planning to touch and play with the Pioneers a lot during the encore, so please look forward to the encore live as well.
ということで、えっと、えっと、そう、いろいろ、いろんなことやらなきゃいけないから、水を飲みます。
And so, um, um, yes, I have to do various things, so I'm going to drink some water.
あ、水美味しい。ライブと言ったら水だよね。
Ah, the water is good. Water is a must for a live, right?
ということで、どんどん今日は盛り上がっていきたいと思います。その前に、ちょっと待ってね。
So, I want to keep the excitement going today. Before that, wait a moment.
じゃん！
Ta-da!
こちらの猫耳をつけて、え、みんなと一緒に盛り上がっていきたいと思います！
I'm going to put on these cat ears and get excited with everyone!
ということで、次の曲はこの曲です。聞いてください。「ω猫」。
So, the next song is this one. Please listen. "Omega Neko."
ワン・ツー・にゃん、はい！
One, two, nyan, here we go!
（にゃっぷー！）
(Nyappu!)
三食お昼寝完備はあたりまえ！
Three meals and naps fully provided is a given!
（にゃんにゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん！にゃんだふぉー！）
(Nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan! Nyandafull!)
あとたまに褒めナデナデも所望する！
And sometimes I desire praise and pets!
（にゃんにゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん！にゃんだふぉー！）
(Nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan! Nyandafull!)
そしたら十字の愛をあげます
Then I'll give you ten-fold love
君にキュンとしてもらいます
I'll make your heart throb
君とずっとしあわせを育てます
I'll nurture happiness with you forever
（にくきゅー！きょーきゅー！むぎゅー！むぎゅー！）
(Paw pads! Supply! Squeeze! Squeeze!)
キュート盛り　吾輩こそ猫である！
Peak cuteness, I am indeed a cat!
（にゃん　うにゃんにゃんにゃん！にゃんだふぉー！）
(Nyan unyan nyan nyan! Nyandafull!)
特別な君に　触ることを許可する！
I grant special you permission to touch me!
（にゃん　うにゃんにゃんにゃん！にゃんだふぉー！）
(Nyan unyan nyan nyan! Nyandafull!)
素直になれない　本音のしっぽを
My tail of true feelings that can't be honest
追いかけて　優しくつかんでほしい
I want you to chase it and catch it gently
かまってくれなきゃ寂しいにゃん
If you don't pay attention to me, I'll be lonely, nyan
（にゃん！）
(Nyan!)
他の子見てたらおけないにゃん
I won't allow you to look at other girls, nyan
（にゃん！）
(Nyan!)
ヒトのルールとか知らないにゃん
I don't know human rules, nyan
（にゃん！）
(Nyan!)
僕が一番カワイイにゃん！
I'm the cutest one, nyan!
にゃんにゃんにゃん！君とずっとずっといたいので
Nyan nyan nyan! I want to be with you forever and ever,
ボクに首輪をしといてね？
so please put a collar on me, okay?
（にゃんにゃんにゃん！）
(Nyan nyan nyan!)
理解ってないね？そんなのなくたって　ボクは君の運命のにゃんにゃん！
You don't understand, do you? Even without that, I'm your fated nyan nyan!
にゃんにゃんにゃん！夢がさめてしまうまで　鈴の鳴るたびかまってね？
Nyan nyan nyan! Until the dream wakes, every time the bell rings, pay attention to me, okay?
（にゃんにゃんにゃん！）
(Nyan nyan nyan!)
君の愛のぜんぶをください
Give me all of your love
そしたら絶対絶対にゃんにゃん！にゃんだふぉー！
Then I'll definitely, definitely be meow-meow! Meow-nderful!
にゃんってかまって！にゃんにゃん！
Give me attention with a meow! Meow-meow!
アルファ・ベータ・ガンマ　変遷たどれば
Alpha, Beta, Gamma, if we follow the changes
とーぜん到達だ！目指すはオメガ
Of course we'll reach it! Our goal is Omega
君ときたいから　果てまでラブ
Because I want to go with you, love to the end
だって、ωは猫マーク！！！！
Because, ω is a cat mark!!!!
臆病で迷いがちな　ちいさなハートを
A small heart that's cowardly and prone to getting lost
受けとめて　両腕で包んでほしい
Accept it, I want you to wrap your arms around it
これでも愛情表現にゃん！（にゃん！）
This is my way of showing love, meow! (Meow!)
てかそれそろそろ気づいてにゃん！（にゃん！）
By the way, notice it already, meow! (Meow!)
他人の言葉とか知らないにゃん！
I don't care about others' words, meow!
ぼくが一番だいすきにゃん！（にゃん！）
I love you the most, meow! (Meow!)
にゃんにゃん！君とずっとずっといたいので
Meow-meow! Because I want to be with you forever and ever
ボクに首輪をしといてね？（にゃんにゃんにゃん！）
So put a collar on me, okay? (Meow-meow-meow!)
理解ってないね？そんなのなくたって
You don't understand, do you? Even without that
ボクは君の運命のにゃんにゃん！
I'm your destiny, meow-meow!
にゃん！君に愛を尽くすから
Meow! Because I'll give you all my love
ほかに浮気はしないでね？（にゃんにゃん！）
Don't cheat on me, okay? (Meow-meow!)
理解ってしまった！触れた瞬間に
I've realized! The moment we touched
君はボクの運命のにゃんにゃん！
You're my destiny, meow-meow!
にゃん！にゃん！夢がいつか叶うまで
Meow! Meow! Until the dream comes true one day
猫の手を借りまくってね？（にゃんにゃんにゃん！）
Borrow all the cat help you need, okay? (Meow-meow-meow!)
君の愛のぜんぶをください
Give me all of your love
そしたらずっとずっとにゃんにゃん！にゃんだふぉー！
Then forever and ever, meow-meow! Meow-nderful!
にゃんってかまって！にゃんにゃん！
Give me attention with a meow! Meow-meow!
もっとかまって！にゃんにゃん！
Give me more attention! Meow-meow!
FreeGeo
作詞・作曲・編曲：Twinfield
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Twinfield
もっと世界中で　ただ優しい　笑顔を見たいんだ
I want to see more of those simple, kind smiles all over the world
心まで響かせて
Let it resonate to your heart
物語は何度だって続くよ
The story will continue again and again
ずっともっと　歌っていたいよ
I want to keep singing forever and ever
重なっていくほどに強くなるの
It gets stronger the more it overlaps
一歩ずつ進んでく
Stepping forward one by one
旅路はまだ途中だよ
The journey is still in progress
遠く離れていても　消えない未来があるんだ
Even if we're far apart, there's a future that won't fade away
少しずつ変わっても　繋がって奏でてくんだ
Even if it changes little by little, we'll stay connected and keep playing
雨の日も晴れの日も　この想いが届くように
In rain or shine, so that these feelings reach you
見つけてあげるよ
I'll find you
想い出の数だけ描く
As many as there are memories
フレーズは軌跡
The phrases are a trajectory
メロディは止まらないよ
The melody won't stop
好きなんだこの場所でまた
I love being in this place again
Ah Ah 笑顔のままで会いましょう
Ah Ah, let's meet again with smiles on our faces
想像した以上に
More than I imagined
まだ伝えたいことがあるんだ
There's still more I want to tell you
「ありがとう」じゃ足りない
Saying 'thank you' is not enough
ありふれた言葉だけど聴いてて
It's an ordinary word, but please listen
探し続けていたんだ
I've been searching for it
心の奥を示すランドマーク
The landmark that points to the depths of my heart
きっとずっと進んでく
I'll definitely keep going forever
旅路は夢じゃないんだ
The journey is not a dream
鼓動速く鳴るような　愛してる景色があるんだ
There's a scenery I love that makes my heart beat faster
少しずつ変わっても　繋がってる奏でてるんだ
Even if it changes little by little, we're connected and playing together
示した先にあるでしょ？
It's at the end of what I pointed to, isn't it?
私の想い届けたいな
I want to deliver my feelings
ここで会いましょう
Let's meet here
想い出の数だけ描く
As many as there are memories
フレーズは軌跡
The phrases are a trajectory
メロディは止まらないよ
The melody won't stop
好きなんだこの場所でまた
I love being in this place again
Ah Ah 笑顔のままで会いましょう
Ah Ah, let's meet again with smiles on our faces
止め処なく溢れていく
Overflowing endlessly
真っ白な地図を見て
Looking at the pure white map
少しずつ埋まってく
It's filling up little by little
色とりどりの音楽
With colorful music
雨の日も晴れの日も　この想いが届くように
In rain or shine, so that these feelings reach you
見つけてあげるよ
I'll find you.
はい、ということで、お眼鏡ことFreeGeoお届けしました！
Yes, and so, we performed 'Omege-Neko' and 'FreeGeo'!
ちょっと張り切りすぎて息が足りなかった...
I was a bit too enthusiastic and ran out of breath...
けどまあライブということで、はい。
But well, it's a live concert, so, yeah.
猫になれましたか？皆さん。
Did you all manage to become cats?
ということで、今日はね、
And so, for today,
こんな素敵なステージを作っていただきました！
they've built this wonderful stage for me!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
なんと、地球儀が回っております。
Believe it or not, the globe is rotating.
地球儀が回っていたり、先ほどは猫耳をつけたり、
The globe is rotating, and I wore cat ears earlier,
そしてこれね、地図のお姉さん帽子もつけてみたり、
and now I'm trying on this 'Map Big Sister' hat,
色々と演出をこだわってみましたが、いかがでしょうか？
we've put a lot of thought into the production, how do you like it?
というわけで、AZKi 5周年を迎えまして、
Anyway, as AZKi reaches her 5th anniversary,
本当に今年はですね、2023年は様々な転機がありました。
this year, 2023, has truly been full of many turning points.
2023年、ジオゲッサーにはまって地図のお姉さんとなりましたけれども、
In 2023, I got hooked on GeoGuessr and became the 'Map Big Sister',
誰がこんな、こんなことになると予想していたでしょうか。
who could have ever predicted things would turn out like this?
そしてね、ありがたいことに、2023年10月4日にですね、
And, thankfully, on October 4, 2023,
ビクターエンタテインメントからメジャーデビューもさせていただきました。
I made my major debut with Victor Entertainment.
歌のお姉さんも頑張っておりますよ。
I'm doing my best as the 'Singing Big Sister' too.
ということで、本当に5周年を迎えられたことに感謝しております。
So, I'm truly grateful for being able to reach my 5th anniversary.
一人では今日ここまで来ることができませんでした。
I couldn't have made it this far on my own.
開拓者のみんながAZKiを作ってくれたと思っています。
I believe that all you Pioneers are the ones who created AZKi.
「with U」は、そんな意味も込めて今日のライブタイトルにしました。
'with U' is the title of today's live, with that meaning in mind.
ということでですね、この後は皆さんお待ちかねのゲストパートに行きたいと思います。
So, after this, I'd like to move on to the guest part that you've all been waiting for.
今日はですね、なんと、かなたんと、沙花叉と、いろはちゃんが来てくれます！
Today, believe it or not, Kanatan, Sakamata, and Iroha-chan are here!
それでは行きましょう！頑張るぞい！
Here we go! Let's do our best!
君は誰とキスをする
With whom will you kiss?
私それともあの娘
Me, or that girl?
君は誰とキスをする
With whom will you kiss?
星を巡るよ純情
Pure heart travelling through the stars
弱虫泣き虫連れて
Bringing along the coward, the crybaby
まだ行くんだと思うわ私
I think I'll still keep going
愛するより求めるより
More than loving, more than wanting
疑うほうがずっとたやすい
It's much easier to doubt
自分が悔しい
I'm frustrated with myself
痛いよ 味方だけど愛してないとか
It hurts. You're my ally, but you don't love me.
守るけどそばにいれないとか
You protect me, but you can't be by my side.
苦い二律背反
Bitter antinomy
今すぐ touch me
Touch me right now
運命ならば繋がせて
If it's destiny, let us be connected
君は誰とキスをする
With whom will you kiss?
私それともあの娘
Me, or that girl?
心揺らす言葉より
More than words that shake the heart
無責任に抱いて限界
Hold me irresponsibly, I'm at my limit
妄想も砂漠を起きて
Waking up from delusions in the desert
後ろから蹴り上げたら
If I kick up from behind
むき出しの恋によろけた
Staggered by an exposed love
呼吸だけで精一杯
Barely able to breathe
迎えに来て溺れてるから
Come and get me, because I'm drowning
痛いよ 前向きな嘘 間に受けるのは
It hurts. Taking a positive lie seriously...
笑ってる声 責められないから
Because I can't blame your laughing voice
未来持てあました
I had more future than I could handle
今すぐ hold me
Hold me right now
理性なんて押し殺して
Crush your reason
君は誰とキスをする
With whom will you kiss?
私それともあの娘
Is it me, or that girl?
涙まるで役立たず
Tears are completely useless
星を駆けるよ純情
My pure heart races through the stars
What is this triangle for?
Triangle, triangle...
君は誰とキスをする
Who will you kiss?
Destiny will be triangle
君は誰とキスをする
Who will you kiss?
私それともあの娘
Is it me, or that girl?
たった一つ命を糧に
With only one life to fuel me
今振りかざす感傷
I brandish my sentiment now
たった一つ命を糧に
With only one life to fuel me
今振りかざす感傷
I brandish my sentiment now
はい、ということで、かなたんと沙花叉と一緒に
トライアングラーを歌わせていただきました！
Yes! So, I sang "Triangular" together
with Kanatan and Sakamata!
ということでかな研集合ー！
So, KanaKen, assemble!
5周年おめでとうー！
Happy 5th Anniversary!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
はい、えっと、あずちゃんの永遠の嫁の天音かなたと...
Yes, I'm Amane Kanata, AZKi-chan's eternal wife...
はい、えー、あずちゃんの元妻の沙花叉クロヱです！
Yes, and I'm Sakamata Chloe, AZKi-chan's ex-wife!
いやちょっと複雑、めちゃめちゃ複雑な関係の
3人でドロドロのかな研で出てきましたけれども
Well, we're a trio with a very messy,
complicated relationship here as KanaKen...
二人とも今日は来てくれてありがとー！
Thank you both for coming today!
呼んでくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you for inviting us!
あずきはかな研で集合してライブがしたいなと思っていて
I've been wanting to have a live concert as KanaKen,
今回一緒にライブができてとっても嬉しかったです。ありがとう！
so I'm very happy we could do it this time. Thank you!
こちらこそありがとうございました。とっても楽しかった！
Thank you as well. It was a lot of fun!
なんかトライアングラー自体、三角形を売る者たちの意味があるらしくて
It seems "Triangular" itself has a meaning
related to those who sell triangles,
沙花叉も3人で歌いたいなと思ってたんですよ。
and I also wanted to sing it as a trio.
ありがたい！実はそう、みんなで選曲を
どうしようかなって考えてるときに
I appreciate that! Actually, while we were
thinking about what songs to pick,
沙花叉からも案をもらって、かなたんにも
意見をもらって、今回実現しました！
I got suggestions from Sakamata and opinions
from Kanatan, and we made it happen!
やったー！
Yay!
本当に、なんか1時間まるごとかな研ライブみたいなのもやっぱしてみたいよね。
I'd really love to do a full hour-long
KanaKen live concert sometime.
いつかね、社長、いつかできますかね、我々。
Someday, right? Boss, can we do it someday?
やりましょう！僕たちが頑張って。
Let's do it! We'll work hard for it.
やりましょう！それと、そうです、かな研でね...
オリジナル曲をね、いつか作りたいなと思ってますよ！
Let's! And also, yes, as KanaKen...
I'd like to make an original song together one day!
マジでそれです！
Exactly!
じゃあまず、かなたんはどんな曲を作りたいですか？
So first, Kanatan, what kind of song
would you want to make?
僕はね、やっぱこの3人だったら、ちょっと可愛い系の曲とかもいいのかなって思うんで...
I think, with the three of us, maybe a cute-style
song would be good...
中毒性があって何度も聴きたくなるような、なんかピコピコ系の曲とか作ってみたいなって思ってる。
I'm thinking of making an addictive, chiptune-style
song that people would want to listen to over and over.
いいですねー、合いそう、二人にも。沙花叉はなんかある？
That's nice! It'd suit you two. How about you, Sakamata?
えー、なんかそれぞれこう、掛け合いとかのセリフがあるような曲だったら...
Well, maybe a song that has dialogue
or call-and-response sections for each of us...
めっちゃいいな！ピコピコとも合いそう！
That sounds great! It would go well with
the chiptune style too!
わかりて、わかりて！歌いたい掛け合い！
I get it, I totally get it! I want to sing
a call-and-response song!
ということで、かな研の音楽への熱い思いも聞けたところで、はい、ありがとうございます。
So, now that we've heard about KanaKen's passion
for music... alright, thank you!
ご褒美で二人はここで、お別れとなりますー。
As a reward, it's time to say goodbye
to these two.
ええー！？
What!?
今日はあずきの5周年ライブに駆けつけてくれて本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to my 5th
anniversary live today!
また一緒に歌おうね、バイバーイ！
Let's sing together again sometime! Bye-bye!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Media stirred up by that invincible smile
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Wanting to know those secrets, so mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her flaws are part of her charm
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You, the perfect liar,
天才的なアイドル様
Are a genius-like idol
「今日何食べた？」
“What did you eat today?”
「好きな本は？」
“What's your favorite book?”
「遊びに行くならどこに行くの？」
“If you were to go out, where would you go?”
「何も食べてない」
“I haven't eaten anything”
「それは内緒」
“That's a secret”
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Dodging every question with ease
そう淡々と
So calmly,
だけど燦々と
But so brilliantly,
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
The secrets that are almost visible taste like honey
あれもないないない
That's not it, no, no, no
これもないないない
This isn't it, no, no, no
好きなタイプは？相手は？さあ答えて
What's your type? Is there someone? Come on, answer
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ」
“I don't really know what it's like to fall in love with someone”
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Unable to tell if it's a lie or the truth,
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
Another person falls for those words,
また好きにさせる
Making them fall in love again
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone is captivated by you,
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You are the perfect and ultimate idol
金利際現れない
Never to appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
The reincarnation of the brightest star
ああ その笑顔で愛してるで
Ah, with that smile and those “I love you”s,
誰も彼も虜にしていく
You're enthralling everyone
その瞳がその言葉が
Those eyes, those words,
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
Even if they're lies, it's a perfect love
はいはいあの娘は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special
我々は端からおまけです
We've been just an extra from the start
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're just the supporting actor B to the star
全てがあの娘のおかげなわけない
There's no way it's all thanks to her
洒落臭い 妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
How annoying! There's no way there isn't envy and jealousy
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, which is why it's unforgivable
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
If you're not perfect, it's unforgivable
自分も許せない
I can't forgive myself either
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't accept anyone but you, who are stronger than anyone
誰もが信じあがめてる
Everyone believes and worships you,
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Truly the strongest and invincible idol
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses can be found,
一番星を宿している
Housing the brightest star within you
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You must never show any weaknesses, no, no
知りたくないとこは見せずに
Without showing the parts people don't want to know,
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
You have to be one of a kind, or it's a no, no
それこそ本物のアイ
That's exactly what true love is
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Warming up the media with your signature smile,
隠し通すこの秘密だけは
Hiding away only this secret,
「愛してる」って嘘で積むキャリア
Building a career on the lie of “I love you”s,
これこそ私なりの愛
This is my own kind of love
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the trickling sweat is beautiful aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
These eyelids that hide rubies,
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria,
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the ultimate love
誰かに愛されたことも
I've never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
And I've never loved anyone either
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること信じてる
I believe that my lies will one day become the truth
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
One day, I'll surely get everything,
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Yes, I'm a greedy idol
等身大でみんなのこと
In my own way, about everyone,
ちゃんと愛したいから
Because I want to love you properly,
今日も嘘をつくの
I'll tell lies again today
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
Wishing for the day these words will one day become the truth
それでもまだ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Even so, I still haven't been able to say it only to you and you,
あやっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it
これは絶対嘘じゃない愛してる
This is definitely not a lie, I love you
うわぁー！
Waaah!
あずきち、5周年、おめでとうでござる！
AZKi-chi, 5th anniversary, congratulations de gozaru!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということでゲストにいろはちゃん来てもらいました！
So, our guest, Iroha-chan is here!
イェーイ！お邪魔するでござるー！
Yay! Thank you for having me de gozaru!
いやー、今日は来てくれてありがとう。
Man, thank you for coming today.
いえいえ、こうやってまた一緒にね、歌って踊れて嬉しいでござるな。
No, no. I'm so happy we could sing and dance together like this again.
ねー、いつもは風真の記念配信に来ていただくことが多いんですけど、
Right? Usually, you come to my anniversary streams a lot, but...
今日はね、あずきの5周年にいろはちゃんをお呼びいたしました！
...today, I invited Iroha-chan to my 5th anniversary!
お邪魔しちゃいましたよ。呼んでもらえてすごい嬉しいでござる！
I'm crashing the party! I'm so happy you invited me!
いやもう、このあずきの5周年にはいろはちゃんがいないと...
I mean, AZKi's 5th anniversary wouldn't be complete without Iroha-chan...
あ、そんな！始まらないなって。
Oh, stop it! ...it wouldn't even start.
そんなこと言っていただきよろしいんですか？
Is it really okay for you to say that?
本当ありがとう。
Really, thank you.
ということで「あずいろ」今年も色々ありましたね。
So, a lot has happened for "Azuiro" this year, hasn't it?
本当になんか結構一緒にいた時間が長い気がするんでござるよな。
I really feel like we've spent quite a lot of time together.
なんとですね、
Actually,
「あずいろ」が結成したのは、
"Azuiro" was formed on...
2022年9月17日ということで、「あずいろ」結成1周年経っておりました！
...September 17, 2022. So it's been one year since Azuiro's formation!
1周年！
Our 1st anniversary!
そうだよ！1周年じゃん！
That's right! It's been a year!
そっか！1周年の日にね！
I see! On our 1st anniversary!
そうでござるな。
Indeed it is.
アンドロイドガールを、あの…投稿した日をね、
The day we posted "Android Girl"...
結成日としまして、なんと1年が経っておりました。
...we set as our formation day, and it's been exactly one year.
あっという間！
In the blink of an eye!
あっという間だね。
It really was.
なんか、でも今年はさらにね、色々な、またさらに歌ってみたも出しまして…
But this year, we released even more "Utattemita" (covers)...
そう！出しましてじゃないもんね。やって！
Yes! Not just released, we did so much!
あん、「アイドル」出して。
Um, we released "Idol".
「アイドル」出して、今日ね、このライブでね、一緒に歌いまして。
Released "Idol", and today, we sang together at this live.
ね！もうかっこいいスクリーンにね！
Right! On such a cool screen!
そう、かっこいいスクリーンに、こちらの球体スクリーンにね、映していただきました。はい。
Yes, on a cool screen, this spherical screen, they projected us. Yes.
映してもらって。はい。で、今年は夏に色々あったな！
They did. And this summer, a lot happened!
「愛してるゲーム」…「愛してるゲーム」とかもした…
I feel like... we played the "I love you" game...
したような気がします…しますね！
I feel like we did... we did!
ね！かき氷も一緒に食べた！
Right! We ate shaved ice together!
かき氷食べて、暑い中で！お買い物もいたし。
Eating shaved ice in the heat! We went shopping too.
お買い物いたし、パンも食べたし。
We went shopping, and ate bread too.
食べたし！はい。
We did! Yes.
んなことをした、今年2023年でございますね。
That's how our 2023 was.
本当に！や、でもあっという間すぎて。
Truly! It went by so fast.
でもこうして5周年にね、こうして呼んでいただけると思っていなかったので、とってもとっても嬉しくて！
But I never thought I'd be invited to your 5th anniversary, so I'm very, very happy!
呼ばれた時からもう本当にもうちょっと、ドキドキドキドキ…ってなってました本当には。嬉しい。
From the moment I was invited, I was like, "thump-thump, thump-thump". Truly. I'm happy.
嬉しい。で、これからも、AZKiちと色々ね、歌も踊りもやっていきたいなって…
I'm happy too. And from now on, I want to do many things with AZKi-chi, like singing and dancing...
あずいろ！これからも、あるってこと？こと？こと？こと？こと？
Azu-Iro! Does that mean we'll keep going? Going? Going? Going? Going?
これからもあります、あずいろ。
We will, Azu-Iro.
なんで、今後ともよろしくお願いします！
So, please continue to support us!
あずいろ、よろしくお願いします！
Please support Azu-Iro!
イェーイ！ピースピースピース！
Yay! Peace, peace, peace!
そして、そして？そして？や、ちょっとすみませんね、こちら関係者のよしみで聞いちゃったんですけど…
And, and? And? Ah, sorry, I heard this through my connections...
なんか、今回新衣装が！そう、あるとかなんです！は！
Apparently, this time, there's a new outfit! Yes, there is! Hah!
なんとAZKi、このあと、新衣装のお披露目をいたします！
Amazingly, AZKi will reveal a new outfit after this!
ええ！いいんですか？いいんですか？
Eh! Is it okay? Is it really okay?
え、ちょっとカメラマンさん。
Wait, Mr. Cameraman.
いろはちゃん、見ててくれる？
Iroha-chan, will you watch me?
もちろんだよ！任せて！
Of course! Leave it to me!
ちょっともう見て！カメラマンに今日は、カメラマンに…あーもう可愛い！可愛い！あ！なんて可愛いんだ！
Look! To the cameraman today... Ah, so cute! So cute! Ah! How can she be so cute!
このあとお披露目いたしますので、ぜひ最後まで見ていてね！
I'll be revealing it after this, so please watch until the end!
皆殿任せてくれ、最高のAZKiち届けるからよ！ありがとう！
Everyone, leave it to me! I'll deliver the best AZKi-chi to you! Thank you!
あ、でもそのためにお着替えが必要でござるな。
Ah, but for that, an outfit change is necessary.
そうなんです。え、ちょっとすみませんカメラさん。ちょっと…
That's right. Uh, excuse me Mr. Cameraman. Just a bit...
はい！今からですね、うちAZKi先輩のお着替えに参りますので、皆殿少々お待ちいただいてよろしいですかね？
Yes! From now on, I'll accompany AZKi-senpai for her outfit change, so could everyone please wait for a moment?
はい！それではお着替えに行ってきます！
Yes! We're going to change outfits now!
はい！先に見てきます！皆殿もお楽しみに！楽しみに！じゃ、行くぞ！
Yes! I'll see it first! Everyone, look forward to it! Look forward to it! Let's go!
お着替え！お着替え！お着替え！お着替え！
Outfit change! Outfit change! Outfit change! Outfit change!
知らない言葉を覚えていくたび
Every time I learn a word I didn't know
Sincerely
作詞：唐沢美帆　作曲：堀江晶太
Lyrics: Miho Karasawa Composition: Shouta Horie
面影の中　手を伸ばすの
I reach out my hand within the vestiges
だけど一人では分からない言葉も
But there are words I can't understand alone
あるのかもしれない
Perhaps they exist
さよならは苦くて
Goodbye is bitter
「愛してる」は遠い匂いがした
"I love you" smelled like something distant
例えようのない　この思いは
This inexpressible feeling
とても怖くて　だけどとても愛おしくて
Is very scary, yet very precious
私なんで泣いてるんだろう
Why am I crying?
心になんて答えたらいい
How should I answer my heart?
言葉はいつでも語るでもなく
Words don't always speak
そこにあるばかり　募るばかり
They just exist there, just growing
私はあなたに会いたくなる
I start wanting to see you
綺麗な言葉を覚えていくたび
Every time I learn a beautiful word
自分のことが嫌になりそう
I feel like I'm starting to hate myself
だけど背を向けちゃいけない言葉も
But there are words I must not turn my back on
あるのかもしれない
Perhaps they exist
Sincerely
悲しみは冷たく
Sadness is cold
「ありがとう」は
"Thank you"
ぬくもりに色づく
Takes on the color of warmth
形のないもの
Intangible things
触れるたびに
Every time I touch them
あなたの声が
Your voice
胸の奥で響いているの
Resonates deep within my heart
書きかけてはやめた
I started writing then stopped
宛先のない手紙が今
A letter with no destination now
風に揺れる
Sways in the wind
届けたい人の街まで
To the town of the person I want to reach
始まりの終わりを
The end of the beginning
伝えるために
Just so I can tell you
生きることを
That I'll live on
やめないことを
And I won't give up
あなたに今日を
So that today
誇れるように
I can make you proud
私なんで泣いてるんだろう
I wonder why I'm crying
心になんて
How should I
答えたらいい
Answer my heart?
言葉はいつでも
Words are always
語るでもなくて
Not just for speaking
そこに在るばかり
They just exist there
募るばかり
Only growing stronger
私はあなたに
I find myself
会いたくなるよ
Wanting to see you
はい！
Yes!
ということで、皆さんお待たせいたしました！
And with that, sorry to keep you all waiting!
新衣装、こちらになります！
Here is my new outfit!
みんな、どう？
What do you all think?
はーい！
Hi!
どうでしょうか？どうでしょうか？
How do I look? How do I look?
ということで、お送りした曲は
TRUEさんの「Sincerely」でした！
The song I just performed was
'Sincerely' by TRUE!
どうですか？
What do you think?
えー、今回の新衣装のテーマはですね、
Um, the theme for this new outfit is...
「コンサートドレス」をテーマに仕立てていただきました。
It was designed with a 'concert dress' theme.
普段とは違った、豪華な、ね、装いとなってます。
It's a more luxurious look than usual, right?
どうですか？後ろも、
How is it? And the back...
どうですか？どうですか？
How is it? How is it?
え、予想はみんな、どうでしたか？
So, how were your predictions?
あ、コメントたくさんありがとうございます。
Oh, thank you for all the comments.
お、女神？え、本当に？本当に？
Oh, a goddess? Really? Truly?
最高？あ、素晴らしい、好き、最高です。ありがとう、みんな。
The best? Oh, wonderful, love it, it's great. Thank you, everyone.
どんな、じゃ、ここからはちょっとね、
あの、スクショタイムということで。
Well then, from here on out,
it's time for some screenshots.
あ、今回ね、場所を変えて、このラミィちゃんのステージで。
Oh, I've changed locations to Lamy-chan's stage for this.
今日ラミィちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Lamy-chan, happy birthday today!
そんな、あの、運命の11月15日ということで、
ちょっとラミィちゃんのステージをお借りして、
Since it's that fateful November 15th,
I'm borrowing Lamy-chan's stage
お届けさせていただいております。ということで。
to bring this to you.
お綺麗、お綺麗、ありがとうございます。
Beautiful, so beautiful. Thank you.
じゃあ、スクショタイムということで。
Now, let's have that screenshot time.
あ、実はね、そう、ちょっと紹介が遅れましたが、
Oh, actually, I'm a bit late in mentioning this,
マイクもこの衣装に合わせて作っていただいたんですよ。
but the microphone was also made to match this outfit.
見て見て。
Look, look.
可愛いマイクになっております！
It's such a cute microphone!
いや、あと、スタンドもね、可愛く、綺麗に作っていただきました。
And the stand too, they made it so cute and beautiful.
どんなポーズがいいですか？
What kind of poses should I do?
なんかね、今日のこのステージにも合ってるね。
It really matches today's stage, doesn't it?
え、どうかな？
Hmm, how about this?
でも、でもな、ドレスだから、
But since it's a dress...
あ、こんな、こんな、こんな、どうですか？
Maybe like this, or this, or this... How's this?
スクショタイム、いっぱいスクショして、
Screenshot time! Take lots of photos
「AZKi5周年ライブ」でポストしてくださいね。
and post them with #AZKi5周年ライブ.
星空マイクと、あと、実はこうね、
The starry sky mic and, actually,
こうティアラとかもね、作ってもらったり、
they even made this tiara and everything,
あとは、あとは、そう、サイドテールに...
and, and also, my side-tail...
髪型もしていただきまして、なんとね。
I also had my hairstyle done, you know.
ちゃんと、そう、色がインナーカラーが入ってるんですよ、なんと。
And look, there's even inner color in it, for real.
グラデーションで。
With a gradation.
可愛いでしょう？可愛いでしょう？
Isn't it cute? Isn't it cute?
床になっとる。床になってますね、みんな。
You've become the floor. You're all the floor now.
全方位。くるりと。
From all directions. Let me spin around.
くるくると。
Round and round.
どうですか？
How is it?
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
みんな、床になっとるなっとる。
Everyone's becoming the floor, becoming the floor.
はい、というわけで、新衣装ね。
Alright, so, about this new outfit...
ちょうど昨年の11月15日に新ビジュアル変更しまして、
We changed to the new visual exactly on November 15th last year,
そこから1年が経ちまして、
and since then, a year has passed.
この素敵なね、本当に歌を歌うのにぴったりな新衣装を仕立てていただきました！
And I had this wonderful new outfit, perfect for singing, made for me!
床にならざるを得ない。ありがとう。ありがとうございます。
You can't help but become the floor. Thank you. Thank you very much.
今日は床が広い。確かに今日は床が広いね。
The floor is wide today. Indeed, the floor is wide today.
いや、なので、ぜひ新しいこんなAZKiも、ぜひ好きになってくれたら嬉しいです。
So, I'd be happy if you could come to like this new AZKi as well.
はい。
Yes.
るんるん。
Run-run.
私は床です。
I am the floor.
みんな床に、床になってる。
Everyone's on the floor, becoming the floor.
あ、じゃちょっと待って。次の曲に行く前にね、ちょっとお水を飲んでね。
Ah, wait a moment. Before moving to the next song, let me drink some water.
ここ湖だからね、お水はたっぷりありますということで。
This is a lake, so there's plenty of water here.
はい、水も飲んで。
Alright, water finished.
それでは新たな衣装でですね、気持ちも新たに、
Now, with this new outfit and a fresh feeling,
この衣装に合う曲を歌っていこうかなと思います。
I'm going to sing a song that matches this outfit.
はい。それでは次の曲、聴いてください。
Yes. Now, please listen to the next song.
藍深く。
Ai Fukaku.
藍深く
Deep Indigo
作詞・作曲・編曲：keeno
Lyrics/Music/Arrangement: keeno
目を閉じて耳を塞いで
Closing my eyes, covering my ears
やっと君を閉じ込めたのに
I finally locked you away, but...
繰り返してる呼吸に混ざって
Mixing into my repeated breaths,
少しずつ零れてしまいそうで
it feels like it's spilling out little by little.
いっそこのまま
I'd rather just stay like this,
誰にも届かない深い夜の底で
at the bottom of a deep night where no one can reach,
息を止めてしまいましょう
and just stop breathing.
トクントクンと涙のかわりに
Thump-thump, instead of tears,
悲しくなるほど音を立てる心臓
my heart makes a sound that's heartbreakingly loud.
分かっているの 分かっているのだけど
I know, I know, but...
まだこんなにも 君をただこんなにも
still, this much, just this much, for you...
口を噤んで膝を抱えて
Shutting my mouth, hugging my knees,
そろそろ泣いてもいいですか？
is it okay if I start crying soon?
繰り返す脈の行き着く先まで
Until the destination of my repeating pulse,
私の全部に君がいた
you were in all of me.
もう二度と君に触れられないこんな身体なら意味はなくて
If this body can never touch you again, it has no meaning,
今すぐにでも脱ぎ捨ててしまいたいのに
and yet, I want to cast it off right now.
もがいてもどうしようもなくて
No matter how I struggle, there's nothing I can do,
酷く膿んだこの傷を掻き毟っている
and I'm scratching at this terribly festering wound.
いっそこのまま
I'd rather just stay like this,
私にはいらない
I don't need it,
暗い夜の後ろで息をしてる
breathing behind the dark night.
明日なんて
As for tomorrow...
このまま泣いて全部零れたら
If I cry like this and everything spills out,
君を知らない私になれるのかな
will I be able to become a "me" who doesn't know you?
トクントクンと涙が涸れても
Thump-thump, even if the tears dry up,
この身体中を巡る焼けるような赤
the burning red that circulates throughout this body...
分かっているの 分かっているのだけど
I know, I know, but...
これじゃあまりにも この恋があまりにも
this is just too much, this love is just too much...
This is just too much, this love is just too much.
まだこんなにも 君をただこんなにも
Even now, so much, you are just so much...
いのち
Inochi (Life)
息をしている
Breathing,
君は生きている
you are living.
当然のことを
No one doubts
誰も疑わないの
what is natural.
息をしている
Breathing,
表に見えている
visible on the surface.
生の裏側
On the other side of life,
私にとっての何か
something for me.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is thumping.
叩かれても 腐らずに
Even if I'm beaten, I won't decay.
ここで歌うよ ボタン一つの 命
I'll sing here, a life of a single button.
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの
I feel like I'm about to disappear,
わかってよ わかってよ ねえ
understand me, understand me, hey.
本当はどこなの
Where is it really?
恋と愛は違うんでしょ？
Love and affection are different, right?
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget,
私は いなくなるの 命
I will be gone... life.
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye.
息をしている だから生きている
Breathing, so I am living.
自己証明を 欲しがって
I want,
欲しがっているんだ
I'm wanting to prove myself.
音が止まって 動かなくなって
The sound stopped and I can't move.
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll laugh at me then.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is thumping.
嫌われても 腐らずに
Even if I'm hated, I won't decay.
ここで歌うよ 気分次第の 命
I'll sing here, a life at the mercy of my mood.
最後まで私のこと見届け続けてくれるの？
Will you keep watching over me until the very end?
冷めてしまいそうなの
I feel like I'm about to cool down,
わかってよ わかってよ ねえ
understand me, understand me, hey.
声が聞こえるんだよ
I can hear your voice,
塩辛い涙が出ちゃうほど
so much that salty tears come out.
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget,
私は いなくなるの 命
I will be gone... life.
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye.
塞ぎ込んだあの日を 軽く弄らないで やめて
Don't poke fun at those days when I was depressed, stop it.
それが生きる糧になるから
Because that becomes the food for living.
大丈夫 ずっと私は 歌い続けるから
It's okay, I'll keep singing forever.
最後まで私は
I don't know if I'll be alive
生きているか分からないけど
until the very end,
君がくれた言葉は 確かに残ってる
but the words you gave me certainly remain.
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
一緒に死んでしまうだろう
We might die together,
わかんない わかんないよ ねえ
I don't know, I don't know, hey.
痛いくらい気持ちが
There are times when our feelings
シンクロする時もあるけど
synchronize so much it hurts.
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget,
私は いなくなるの 命
I will be gone... life.
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
途中機材トラブルで音が飛んじゃいましたが...
The audio cut out midway due to tech trouble...
この後も聴いてね！
...but please keep listening!
はい！ということで...
Alright! And with that...
アリーナに戻ってきましたー！
I'm back at the Arena!
どう、実は...
So, actually...
ジャケットなしの新衣装バージョンもあるんです。
there's a version of my new outfit without the jacket.
どうでしょうか？ わー！
What do you think? Wow!
ということで、えー...
And so, um...
お聴きいただいたのは、「i-fukaku」と「いのち」でした。
the songs you just heard were "i-fukaku" and "Inochi".
しんみりバラードパートはいかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you like the solemn ballad part?
ということで、ここでお待ちかねのあれを...
So now, I'd like to announce that long-awaited...
告知したいと思います！
...thing!
こちら！
This!
AZKi活動5周年記念フルセット
AZKi 5th Anniversary Full Set
AZKi活動5周年記念グッズ発売します！
AZKi's 5th Anniversary Goods are going on sale!
それでは内容を紹介していきたいと思います。
Now, I'll introduce the contents.
まず、アクリルパネル！
First, the Acrylic Panel!
こちら！
This one!
アクリルパネル
Acrylic Panel
イラストは、ぴすけ先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Pisuke-sensei.
自然の中、歌っているAZKiを明るくて透明感のあるイメージで描いていただきました。
It shows AZKi singing in nature with a bright, clear image.
新しい衣装のAZKiをぜひお家で飾ってください。
Please display this new-outfit AZKi in your home.
そして次、
And next,
開拓者証明書！
the Pioneer Certificate!
開拓者証明書
Pioneer Certificate
こちらもイラストはぴすけ先生。
The illustration for this is also by Pisuke-sensei.
あなたが、開拓者であることを証明するカードになっております。
It's a card that proves you are a Pioneer.
シリアルナンバーと、裏面にはですね、AZKiのメッセージが入っています。
It has a serial number and a message from AZKi on the back.
そして次、
And next,
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
the Random Acrylic Keyholders!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー
Random Acrylic Keyholder
こちらの可愛いミニキャラのイラストは、夢ノ内先生に描いていただきました。
These cute mini-character illustrations were by Yumenouchi-sensei.
新衣装と普段の衣装の、えー、バージョンが全4種類あります。
There are 4 versions in total, including the new outfit.
飾ったりバッグにつけたり、お出かけしてください。
Display them or put them on your bag when you go out.
そして次、
And next,
開拓者ぬいぐるみ！
the Pioneer Plushie!
開拓者ぬいぐるみ
Pioneer Plushie
開拓者3D化を記念して、開拓者がついにぬいぐるみになりました。
To celebrate the Pioneer going 3D, it's now a plushie!
とっても可愛くできております。
It turned out very cute.
「あづぬい」と一緒に並べたりして、楽しんでほしいなと思います。
I hope you enjoy lining it up with your "Azunui".
そして次、
And next,
記念ボイス！
the Memorial Voice!
記念ボイス
Memorial Voice
新衣装に合わせた内容のシチュエーションボイスとなっております。
It's a situation voice matching the new outfit.
気持ちを込めて収録したので、ぜひ聴いてください。
I put my heart into recording it, so please give it a listen.
そしてなんと！
And what's more!
フルセットご購入いただいたら、こちら！
If you buy the full set, you get this!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
直筆サイン入りのポストカードを、なんと全員に書きます！
I will hand-sign postcards for everyone!
AZKi頑張ります！メッセージは届いてからのお楽しみです。
AZKi will do her best! The message is a surprise.
そして、特典ボイスもついてきます。
It also comes with a bonus voice.
5周年ありがとうのメッセージ、感謝の気持ちをお届けできればと思っています。
I hope to deliver my gratitude for the 5th anniversary.
受注はこの後21時から、よろしくお願いします。
Pre-orders start at 21:00. Thank you!
そして、まだあります！嬉しいお知らせその2！
And there's more! Happy news part 2!
こちら！
This!
ホロライブ公式スタンプ「AZKi」
Official Hololive Stickers "AZKi"
ホロライブ公式スタンプ「AZKi」が本日より発売開始いたします！
Official Hololive stickers "AZKi" go on sale today!
「おはあず」から「おやすあず」まで、全24種類。
"Oha-Azuki" to "Oyasu-Azuki", 24 types in total.
ぜひゲットして、たくさん使ってください！
Please get them and use them a lot!
ということで、お知らせ、まだあります。告知のおさらいになります。
There's still more news. A recap of previous announcements.
SorAZ メジャーデビューライブ「First Gravity」。
SorAZ Major Debut Live "First Gravity".
SorAZ Major Debut Live First Gravity
2024年1月27日、CLUB CITTA'にて開催いたします。
It will be held at CLUB CITTA' on January 27, 2024.
現地チケット、二次先行が11月19日、23時59分まで。
Local ticket second pre-sale is until Nov 19, 23:59.
そして、オフィシャルグッズもございます。
And there are also official goods.
オフィシャルグッズ
Official Goods
11月26日、23時59分まで発売となっております。
They are on sale until Nov 26, 23:59.
ライブ当日までにお届けしますので、詳しくは概要欄をご覧ください。
They'll be delivered by the live. Check the description.
SorAZのリアルライブ、よろしくお願いします！
Please support the SorAZ live!
ということで、怒涛の告知でしたけれども、
So, that was a flurry of announcements...
次の曲で、最後になります。
...but the next song will be the last.
改めて、5周年を迎えられたことに感謝してます。
Once again, I'm grateful for my 5th anniversary.
このルートに辿り着いたことは、間違いじゃなかった。
Reaching this route... it wasn't a mistake.
開拓者の皆んなが連れてきてくれました。
The Pioneers brought me here.
だから、今日は最後にこの曲を届けます。
So, for the finale today, I'll deliver this song.
この曲から、AZKiは始まりました。
AZKi began with this song.
今日この日を、AZKiと一緒に過ごしてくれて、ありがとう。
Thank you for spending this day with AZKi.
皆んなと一緒にこれからも。聴いてください。
Together with everyone from here on. Please listen.
「Creating World」。
"Creating World".
この扉の向こう側
Beyond this door
無限の可能性なら 今動き出せるの
If there are infinite possibilities, I can start moving now
暗闇を手探りで
Groping in the dark
不安と焦燥の中 こぼれる光を見た
In anxiety and impatience, I saw the overflowing light
手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand
この先は君のものだから
Because the future belongs to you
時を越えて
Crossing time
繋がるよ 心が今
Our hearts connect now
想像するのは私のストーリー
Imagining my story
声を聞かせて 君を知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you
輝かせよう新しい世界
Let's make a new world shine
生まれた意味を 見つけるのさ
I'll find the meaning of being born
全てが始まる この場所で
Everything begins in this place
声が枯れるまで叫んで
Scream until your voice goes hoarse
言葉に傷つけられ
Hurt by words
悲しみがこぼれるのは 弱いからじゃないよ
And sadness overflowing isn't because you're weak
勇気はここにあるから
Courage is here
かき消されちゃだめなんだ 君は君のままでいい
Don't let it be drowned out, you're fine just as you are
扉を開けて
Open the door
私たちの歌は壊れない
Our song won't break
何度だって
Time and time again
伝えるよ 鼓動を今
I'll convey the heartbeat now
共鳴するのは私のストーリー
Resonating is my story
名前を呼んで そばにいるから
Call my name, because I'm by your side
音を奏でよう新しい世界
Let's play music in a new world
君に出会うために 生きてゆくんだ
I live to meet you
この場所が奇跡だから
Because this place is a miracle
リアルを超えて 繋ぐよ さあ
Beyond reality, I'll connect, come on
夜は深く眠りに落ちて
The night falls into a deep sleep
やがて光が世界を照らすよ
And soon light will illuminate the world
君と出会えたこと
Meeting you
意味を見つけたのさ 共に分かち合って生きたい
I found meaning, I want to live sharing it with you
想像するのは私のストーリー
Imagining my story
声を聞かせて 君を知りたいから
Let me hear your voice, because I want to know you
開拓するの新しい世界
Pioneering a new world
嘘じゃないんだ 君とのストーリー
It's not a lie, the story with you
全てが始まる この場所で
Everything begins in this place
歌を歌い続けるよ
I'll keep on singing
今日はAZKi 5周年ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to AZKi's 5th anniversary live today!
6年目もよろしくお願いします！
Please support me in my 6th year too!
AZKiでしたー！
This was AZKi!
予告
Teaser
AZKi
新企画
New Project
それは、AZKi本人の一言から始まった
It all started with a single comment from AZKi herself
私、GeoGuessrが大好きなんですよ。
I really love GeoGuessr.
私、GeoGuessrを愛してるんですよ。
I love GeoGuessr.
もう私、GeoGuessrでGuessした場所にロケに行きたいんです
I want to go on location to the places I've guessed in GeoGuessr.
えっ！待って！
Wait, what!?
ここから...
From here...
えっ！待って！
Eh! Wait!
初めてのぶらりロケ
My first wandering location shoot
え、これ見たことある
Wait, I've seen this before.
わー
Waah
頬張りすぎた...
I stuffed my cheeks too much...
まさかの洞窟探検も！？
Could there even be cave exploration!?
AZKi 初めてのロケに行ってきました！
AZKi went on her first-time location shoot!
こうご期待！！
Stay tuned!!
今日はAZKiの5周年ライブに来てくれてありがとう。
Thank you for coming to AZKi's 5th Anniversary Live today.
新衣装はどうだったかな？ 似合ってたかな？
What did you think of the new costume? Did it look good on me?
5周年はAZKiにとっても、大きな一歩になったと思います。
I think the 5th anniversary was a big step for AZKi as well.
開拓者のみんながいなかったら、今日この日を迎えることは
If it weren't for all the Pioneers, this day would never have come.
ありませんでした。素敵な景色を見せてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for showing me such a wonderful sight.
これからも、あなたがいるから、AZKiがここにいるよ。
AZKi will continue to be here because you are here.
6年目もよろしくね。 2023.11.15 AZKi
I look forward to our 6th year together. 2023.11.15 AZKi
5周年記念 & 新衣装お披露目ライブ
5th Anniversary Live & Unveiling of New Costume